……相处融洽。
... getting along.
我要找维尔纳齐格勒。
I'm calling for Werner Ziegler.
你认为会发生什么？
What did you think was gonna happen?
我从来没有想到过。
It was never up to me.
当我找到他的时候
When I found him,
他在电话里。
he was on the phone
和一个有利害关系的人在一起。
with an interested party.
你知道是谁吗？
You have any idea who it was?
我知道。
I do.
我就不练习了
I'm not gonna be practicing
以麦吉尔的名字命名。
under the name McGill.
等等，吉米！什么？
Wait, Jimmy! What?
一切都很好，伙计。
It's all good, man.
我本善良@ade字幕
翻译：我本善良@ade
校对：htd211@163.com
警官：在人行道上的黑色福特野马。
OFFICER: Black Ford Mustang on sidewalk...
和喷雾罐，呃，是步行起飞的。
and spray cans, uh, took off on foot.
亚洲男性，没有视觉……
Asian male, no visual...
调度员：10-4。
DISPATCHER: 10-4.
警官2：噪音投诉，6165……
OFFICER #2: Noise complaint, 6165...
当你被石头砸到的时候，你会得到报酬
♪ Getting paid for working when you're stoned ♪
法国吐司没成功，是吧？
French toast didn't work out, huh?
哦，是的。
Oh, yeah.
我很好。
I-It's fine.
我可以帮你暖和一下。
I can warm it up for you.
它是。没关系。
It's... It's okay.
我可以给你弄点别的。
I can get you something else.
我们现在正在供应午餐。
We're serving lunch now.
我很好。
I'm good.
真的。
Really.
我能帮你重新整理一下吗？
Can I at least freshen that for you?
是的，嗯。
Yeah. Um...
谢谢。
Thanks.
嗨，莫莉。是，呃，我。吉恩。
Hi, Molly. It's, uh, me... Gene.
这是你的手机号码吗？
This your cell number?
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry about that.
是的，我。我很好。
Yeah, I... I'm fine.
这是一个错误的警报。
It was a false alarm.
你知道，嗯，原来我只是脱水了，所以。
You know, um, turns out I was just dehydrated, so...
你能相信吗？
Can you believe it?
是的，我肯定会的。
Yeah, I definitely will.
嗯，嘿，呃，我不会回来……呃，直到星期四。
Um, hey, uh, I won't be back for... uh, well, till Thursday.
你和弗雷德里卡能开吗？
Can you and Frederica open?
哦，很好。
Oh. Good.
而且，嗯，我认为你必须要签署
And, um, also, I think you're gonna have to sign
今天下午送货。
for a delivery this afternoon.
哦，你已经说过了？
Oh, you did already?
太好了，谢谢你。
Great. Thank you.
嗯，哦，
Um, oh, and
有人问过我吗？
has anybody been asking about me?
你知道，我的意思是，像任何顾客一样
You know, I mean, like any customers
到商店来找我，有人在附近闲逛吗？
come to the store looking for me, somebody hanging around?
不，不，没有错。
No, no, nothing wrong.
我。我接到了一个保险推销员的电话，
I just... I-I got some calls from an insurance salesman,
你知道，爱出风头的人，所以。
you know, the pushy type, so...
那么，没有人吗？
So, nobody at all?
啊。
Ah.
好了，就是这样，嗯。
Well, that's it then. Um...
是的，当然，我会的。
Yeah. Sure. I will.
嗯，我过几天就会见到你。
And, uh, I will see you in a few days.
谢谢，莫莉。
Thanks, Molly.
是的。
Yeah.
953点在邦纳和第四街的仓库里。
953 down at the warehouse on Bonner and 4th,
一个民用两个街区的报告……
report of a civilian two blocks...
区号1094奥罗拉。
District is 1094 Aurora Drive.
10-23……
10-23.
车辆阻塞……
Vehicle blocking...
我的车停在车道上。
van blocking driveway.
10-23……
10-23.
有一个未成年的白人男性。
There's a juvenile white male,
大约4英尺8英寸，70磅……
about 4'8", 70 pounds...
10:10-28。
10-28 on hold.
那应该是0700。
That'd be 0700.
10-23……
10-23.
在6号和5号在第70号的餐厅。
... at restaurant on 6th and 5th at 70th.
欢迎来到我的世界
♪ Welcome to my world ♪
你不进来吗？
♪ Won't you come on in? ♪
奇迹，我想
♪ Miracles, I guess ♪
偶尔也会发生
♪ Still happen now and then ♪
进入我的心
♪ Step into my heart ♪
把你的烦恼抛在脑后
♪ Leave your cares behind ♪
欢迎来到我的世界
♪ Welcome to my world ♪
哦，哦，哦
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
欢迎来到我的世界
♪ Welcome to my world ♪
嘿。
Hey.
嘿！
Hey!
你是我的。
It is you.
我以为是你。
I thought it was you.
我不是很确定，但现在我要近距离观察你。
I wasn't all the way sure, but now that I'm seeing you up close...
当然。
Sure.
是你。
It's you.
伙计，来了。
Come on, man.
我只是想说声你好，我是一个超级粉丝。
I just want to say hi. I'm a big fan.
你知道，在那一天，
Y'know, back in the day,
当我和我的前男友住在阿尔伯克市时，
when I lived in Albuquerque with my ex,
我过去常在任何地方见到你。
I used to see you everywhere.
你在广告牌上，在电视上。
You were on the billboards, on the TV.
我曾经有一本你的火柴书。
I used to have one of your matchbooks.
你把我弄混了。
You got me mixed up with someone.
呃，我叫塔卡维奇。
Uh, my name is Takavic.
基因
Gene Takavic.
对不起。
Sorry.
我要。我要回去工作了。
I'm... I'm gonna... I got to get back to work.
来吧，伙计。
Come on, man.
这并不酷。
That's not cool.
我知道你是谁。
I know who you are.
你知道你是谁。
You know who you are.
让我们过去吧。
Let's just get past that.
别担心他，他很酷，
Don't worry about him. He's cool.
他只是想过来。
He just wanted to come along.
嘿，你知道我的车里有谁吗？
Hey, you know who I had in my cab once?
萨米哈格！
Sammy Hagar!
他比你更出名。
He's even more famous than you.
你…你想要什么？
Whad'you... Whad'you want?
我只是想让你承认。
I just want you to admit it.
我不知道你是什么
I-I don't know what you're...
你当然知道。
Sure you do.
就说出来吧。
Just say it.
我真的不知道。
I-I really don't know what...
来吧。
Come on.
来吧，伙计。
Come on, man.
说，它。
Say. It.
“最好叫索尔”。
"Better Call Saul".
什么？
What?
我都听不清
I-I can't even hear that.
“最好叫索尔”。
"Better Call Saul".
再来一次。
Once again.
然后。做点什么。
And... And do the point.
“最好叫索尔”。
"Better Call Saul".
我们开始。
There we go.
有点生锈，
A little rusty,
但是，你下次会做得更好。
but  you'll do better next time.
你没有问，但这个名字是杰夫。
You didn't ask, but the name's Jeff.
无论何时你需要我，
Anytime you need me,
你只要打电话给奥马哈联合出租车就行了。
you just call up Omaha United Cabs.
你要我。
You ask for me.
不管我在哪里，他们都会找到我的。
They'll find me, no matter where I'm at.
不超过五分钟。
Never more than five minutes away.
哦，天哪。
Oh, man.
很高兴见到你。
It's great to meet you.
这是一种荣幸。
It's an honor.
我……我去看看你。
I... I'll see ya.
“基尼”。
"Gene".
请再存50美分。
Please deposit an additional 50 cents.
艾德：质量最好的真空吸尘器。
ED: Best Quality Vacuum.
-我能帮你吗？-是的，我需要一个适配器
- How may I help you? - Yeah. I need an adapter
对于一个胡佛MaxExtract吸尘器，型号60。
for a Hoover MaxExtract Pressure-Pro, model 60.
啊哈。
Aha.
我们以前给过你，不是吗？
We've delivered to you before, haven't we?
是的，我在内斯加州的奥马哈市。
Yeah. I'm in Omaha, Nebraska.
塔卡维奇先生。
Mr. Takavic.
这将是一个非常困难的部分。
That will be a very difficult part to obtain.
我想警告你们
And I want to warn you
它会比原来的更贵。
it's gonna be more expensive than the original.
有多贵？
How expensive?
价格翻倍。
Double the price.
我们仍然处于现金交付的状态。
And we are still in a cash-on-delivery situation.
呃……会有问题吗？
Uh... will that be a problem?
不，不，很好。
No. No. It's fine.
好了。
Alright.
你有多热？
How hot are you?
我被造出来了。
I got made.
你被创造了，好吧。
You got made. Alright.
有官方的参与吗？
Any official involvement?
不，还没有。
No. Not yet.
将会是
Pick-up is going to be
在同一个地方，你掉了下来。
in the same place you were dropped off.
你还记得那是什么地方吗？
Do you remember where that is?
是的，我有。
Yeah, I do.
好了，塔卡维奇先生。
Alright, Mr. Takavic.
星期四。
Thursday.
早上7:00
7:00 a.m.
同一地点。
Same spot.
你知道其余的。
You know the rest.
我说的对吗？
Am I right?
Takavic先生？
Mr. Takavic?
还在吗？
Still there?
我改变了主意。
I've changed my mind.
改变了你的想法？
Changed your mind?
是的。
Yeah.
需要说明的是，你不打算这么做吗？
To be clear, you are not going forward with this?
我自己来修。
I'm gonna fix it myself.
风骚律师   第五季  第1集
better  call  saul
女：我们只需要名字。
WOMAN: We just need the name for...
索尔古德曼，S-A-U-L…
Saul Goodman. S-A-U-L...
没有中间的初始？
No middle initial?
你仍然需要签署官方文件
You'll still need to sign official documents
用你的合法名字。
with your legal name.
保持这个想法，一秒。
Hold that thought. One sec.
-吉米，什么。-金姆。
- Jimmy, what... - Kim.
-你是什么。-听着。
- What are you... - Listen.
我知道这似乎很快。
I know this seems fast.
虽然速度很快，但我能看到。
It is fast, but I can see it.
你在改变你的名字？
You're changing your name?
不！我。嗯，是的，但这是给我的客户的。
No! I... Well, yes, but it's for my clients.
-你会称自己为“索尔古德曼”吗？
- - You're gonna call yourself "Saul Goodman"?
我已经称自己为索尔古德曼了。
I'm already calling myself Saul Goodman.
我们已经讨论过了。
We've talked about this.
那些一直在买我手机的人。
The skells who've been buying my phones...
当然，就像射击一样，迟早，
sure as shooting, sooner or later,
他们中的每一个人都会发现自己
every last one of them is gonna find themselves
在一辆警车后座上。
in the back of a squad car.
我怎么让他们给吉米麦吉尔打电话？
How do I get them to call Jimmy McGill?
我不！我是索尔古德曼。
I don't! I stay Saul Goodman.
他们称他们已经认识的人。
They call the guy they already know.
我以为我浪费了一年的生命。
I thought I was wasting a year of my life.
这不是浪费！
It wasn't a waste!
是为了这个！就是这个！
It was for this! This is it!
-你什么时候决定…-刚才，就在后面！
- When did you decide to... - Just now, just back there!
它只是……砰！它击中了我！这是路。
It just... Poom! It just hit me! This is the way.
金姆，它会起作用的。
Kim, it's gonna work.
我。
I...
我知道，我知道。
I know. I know.
突然间，
All of a sudden,
我已经弄明白了，但我……我知道。
I've got it all figured out, but I... I do.
这是对的。
This is right.
所以，让我。我把这个做完，
So, let me just... I'll get this done,
然后我们可以谈论它，好吗？
and then we can talk about it, okay?
我的意思是……
I mean...
除非。
Uh... Unless there's...
我在这里没有看到一些角度吗？
Is there some angle that I'm not seeing here?
如果你想让我放慢速度，
Uh... if you want me to slow my roll,
我可以改天再来。
I-I can come back and do this another day.
如果这就是你的真实感受…
If this is how you're really feeling...
-是。-。我说没问题。
- It is. - ... I say sure.
太好了，五分钟，麦克斯。
Great. Five minutes, max.
好的，我们讲到哪了？
Okay, where were we?
只是你需要签署文件
WOMAN: Just that you need to sign documents
-用你的合法名字-你懂的。
- with your legal name. - You got it.
然后剩下的就是进入的通知。
Then all that's left is the Notice of Entry.
吉米“索尔古德曼”麦吉尔。
Jimmy "Saul Goodman" McGill.
-谢谢你，亲爱的。
- Thank you, honey.
-嗯。-
- Mm-hmm. -
维尔纳齐格勒。
Werner Ziegler.
-维尔纳齐格勒。齐格勒。
- Werner Ziegler. Ziegler. -
你知道德国有多少维尔纳齐格斯吗？
You know how many Werner Zieglers there are in Germany?
27。
27.
根据齐格勒太太的说法，现在是26岁。
26 now, according to Mrs. Ziegler.
我跟你说过，我从来没听说过那个家伙。
I told you I never heard of the guy.
那么“迈克尔”呢？
What about "Michael"?
就像我说的，
Like I said,
我只知道那边两个人的名字。
I only know the names of two guys over there.
是的，是的，是的，是的。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
维克多和泰勒斯。
Victor and Tyrus.
你。
You.
是吗？
Yeah?
维尔纳齐格勒，你听说过那个人吗？
Werner Ziegler. You ever heard of that guy?
维尔纳齐格勒。
Werner Ziegler.
呃……不。
Uh... no.
那么迈克尔呢？
What about Michael?
他是个秃子。
He's a bald gringo.
他在比赛中。
He's in the game.
好的。
Okay.
你很好。
You're good.
好的。
Okay.
南墙，浇筑混凝土。
South wall, pouring concrete.
他在做什么，伙计？
What's he up to, man?
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
所以，没有什么新进展，嗯，
So, there's nothing new going on, huh,
没有什么不同吗？
nothing different?
比如什么？
Like what?
像任何东西一样。
Like anything.
Mnh-mnh.
什么？
What?
没什么。
It's nothing.
没什么，伙计。
It's nothing, man.
四分之一的斯科尔斯
A couple of skells on fourth
一直在抱怨这些东西是被踩上去的。
been complaining that the stuff is stepped on.
-踩了？-嗯。
- Stepped on? - Mm-hmm.
你也听到了吗？
You hear that, too?
他们说这是不同的。
They say it's different.
-不一样？-斯克维尔抱怨道。
- Different how? - Skells complain.
这是他们的工作。
It's what they do.
好的。
Okay.
给我看看。
Show me.
让我们一起去玩"让我们一起去玩"
[DSCHINN'S "LET'S GO TOGETHER" PLAYING]
阿洛！
Arlo!
我的男人！
My man!
三。
Three.
让我们看看你得到了什么。
Let's see what you got.
让我们一起去
♪ Let's go together ♪
嘿！
Hey!
等等，哇，哇！
Wait! Whoa, whoa!
-哇！-引擎熄火了
- Yo! Vato! - [ENGINE SHUTS OFF]
哟！哟！哇！
Yo! Yo! Vato!
你要去哪里？
Where you going?
你不会进去的。
You're not going in there.
-嘿！-
- Yo! -
老鼠，没事的。
Mouse, it's okay.
-那么，这些东西在哪里？
-  - So, where's the stuff?
它在椅子上。
It's in the chair.
什么，这把椅子？
What, this chair?
阿洛：这是关于计数的吗？
ARLO: This about the count?
因为计数很好。
'Cause the count is good.
你持有现金？
You holding cash?
对，就在这里。
Yeah. Got it all right here.
如果你持有我的现金……
If you're holding my cash...
-你拿我的东西在上面干什么？
- what're you doing up here with my stuff? -
没有人踩着它，伙计。
No one's stepping on it, man.
我们从养鸡场里挑东西。
We pick the stuff from the chicken farm.
我们切开它，把它分开，它就在这里。
We cut it, split it, and it lands here.
我一直都是这么做的。
I'm with it all the way.
在他的养鸡场。
At his chicken farm.
你把它捡起来怎么样？
You pick it up how?
他拿出10把钥匙，我选了6个。
He puts out 10 keys. I pick 6.
你如何选择它们？
How do you pick 'em?
我每次都选不同的。
I just pick different ones each time.
它们都是一样的。
They're all the same.
好的，这些。这些都可以。
Okay, so, these... these are okay.
但是这些。
But these...
这大便不是我们的，伙计。
This shit's not ours, man.
这是老式的漂亮。
This is old-school beautiful.
是啊，这是你应得的。
Yeah. You deserve it.
但是，呃。“JMM”。
But, uh... "JMM".
是的。
Yeah.
抱歉，我不知道。
Sorry about that. I didn't know.
我是吉米麦吉尔的。
I got it for Jimmy McGill.
是啊，吉米很喜欢。
Yeah, well, Jimmy loves it.
别担心，我在用它。
And don't worry. I'm using it.
如果，呃，有人说了什么，
If, uh, anybody says anything,
我只说JMM是我的座右铭。
I'll just say JMM is my motto.
你的座右铭？
Your motto?
是的。
Yeah.
“正义……”
"Justice...
最重要的。
Matters Most".
-嗯，不错。-
- Mm, nice. -
还有这个。
There's also this.
哦。
Oh.
哦，是的。
Oh, yeah.
“世界第二最好的律师，再一次”。
"World's 2nd Best Lawyer. Again".
哦，这是真正的错误。世界上最好的律师。
Oh, that's the real mistake... world's second best lawyer...
因为索尔古德曼
because Saul Goodman
会给你钱的。
is gonna give you a run for your money.
我打赌他会的。
I bet he will.
吸入大量
[INHALES SHARPLY]
谢谢。
Thank you.
为了一切。
For everything.
真的。
Really.
你知道吗？
You know what?
真正的诀窍是让我的客户知道
The real trick is gonna be to get my clients to know
那个手机人现在是律师。
that the cellphone guy is now a lawyer...
-他们的律师。-是的。
- their lawyer. - Yep.
那将是一个诡计。
That'll be a trick.
水运行
[WATER RUNNING]
水关闭
[WATER SHUTS OFF]
我想的是，看，
What I'm thinking is, see,
我还剩了一个完整的手机托盘，
I've still got almost a full pallet of cellphones left,
那么，为什么不进行推广呢？
so why not run a promotion?
我要做一个真正的事件。
I-I'll make a real event out of it.
我会把他们送走的，好吗？
I'll... I'll give 'em away, okay?
还有，呃，为了添加甜味剂。
And, uh, for added sweetener...
有限的时间。
limited time only...
嗯，非暴力的重罪，50%。
um, non-violent felonies, 50% off.
你知道，这就像，呃，犯了四个重罪，
You know, it's like, uh, commit four felonies,
你得到了第五个免费的。
you get the fifth one free.
也会有朋友和家人，
And there'll be friends and family, too,
所以你可以分享它们。
so you can share 'em around.
-真的吗？-是的。
- Really? - Yeah.
我的意思是，这只是让人们进门。
I mean, it's just, get people in the door.
一旦他们上钩了，我就会把他们卖掉。
Once they're hooked, I will up-sell them.
这听起来不像是
Doesn't that sound like
你在鼓励这些人犯罪？
you're encouraging these people to commit crimes?
他们不需要鼓励。
They don't need encouragement.
相信我，一勺还是两勺？
Believe me. One scoop or two?
一。
One.
金姆，你不像我一样知道这些混蛋。
Kim, you don't know these assholes like I do.
无论晴雨，这些笨蛋都在那里
Rain or shine, these morons will be out there
做一些愚蠢的事情，并为此而被捕。
doing stupid shit and getting arrested for it.
一点折扣也不会有什么不同。
Little discount won't make a bit of difference.
你想要洒吗？
Do you want sprinkles?
因为我有一些闪光。
'Cause I'm having sprinkles.
嗯，当然。
Uh, sure.
我只是担心这对你有什么影响。
I'm just worried about how this reflects on you.
你知道吗？
You know what?
当你是对的，你是对的。
When you're right, you're right.
我在做什么来降低价格？
What am I doing cutting prices?
折扣是一种绝望的举动。
Discount is a desperation move.
看到了吗？
See?
这就是为什么会这样。
This is why this works.
我走得太远了。
I go too far.
-冰箱门打开-你把我拉回来。
- [REFRIGERATOR DOOR OPENS] - And you pull me back.
你不认为你在推销自己吗？
Don't you think you're selling yourself short?
你很努力地想把你的驾照拿回来。
You worked so hard to get your license back.
我们工作。
We worked.
“因为他是一个快乐的好人”。我们工作。所以，为什么……
- ["FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW" PLAYING] - We worked. So, why be...
为什么。为什么会这样？
Why... Why this?
笑它是完美的。
[CHUCKLING] It's perfect.
他们已经认识我了，我认识他们。
They already know me. I know them.
什么不是爱？
What's not to love?
金，我不能再回去当吉米麦吉尔了。
Kim, I can't go back to being Jimmy McGill.
律师吉米麦吉尔
Jimmy McGill the lawyer
永远都是查克麦吉尔的失败者兄弟。
is always gonna be Chuck McGill's loser brother.
我已经做完了。
I'm done with that.
那个名字被烧毁了。
That name is burned.
这是一个全新的开始。
This is a fresh start.
这就是我前进的方式。
This is how I move forward.
我喜欢它。
And I like it.
我就是看不见它。
It's... I just can't see it.
没关系。
It's okay.
你会的。
You will.
格斯：这是最谨慎的。
GUS: It'll be most discreet.
我可以保证。
That I can guarantee.
我让你久等了吗？
Did I keep you waiting?
我在欣赏古斯塔沃的建立。
I was admiring Gustavo's establishment.
这是巨大的。
It's tremendous.
这么多卡车。
So many trucks.
呃。
Uh...
那些建筑真的是满是鸡吗？
are all those buildings really full of chickens?
唐璜：请坐。
- DON JUAN: Please sit.
有一个严肃的问题要讨论。
There's a serious matter to discuss.
当然，唐璜。
Of course, Don Juan.
你可能已经注意到有些产品是。
You may have noticed that some of the product is...
改变了。
altered.
古斯塔沃会解释。
Gustavo will explain.
我要坦白。
I have a confession to make.
一个男人在为我工作。
A man was working for me.
在我生意的合法方面。
On the legitimate side of my business.
他在监督一个建筑工程。
He was supervising a construction project.
一位德国工程师。
A German engineer.
我想你知道他的名字。
I think you know his name.
维尔纳齐格勒。
Werner Ziegler.
通过监督，
Through an oversight,
齐格勒开始意识到我们的其他活动。
Ziegler became aware of our other activities.
诱惑太大了，他无法抗拒，
The temptation was too great for him to resist,
他偷了两个产品的钥匙。
and he stole two keys of product.
我相信你知道故事的其余部分。
I believe you know the rest of the story.
你知道齐格勒的逃跑。
You know of Ziegler's escape.
你知道我的人跟踪他。
You know that my man tracked him down.
我的耻辱……
My shame...
不仅仅是我允许这样的事情发生。
is not simply that I allowed this to happen.
而是我隐瞒了真相。
It's that I hid the truth.
当我发现齐格勒的所作所为时，
When I discovered what Ziegler had done,
我替换了被盗的产品
I replaced the stolen product
我在当地买了冰毒。
with methamphetamine I purchased locally.
一些劣质产品进入了你的组织。
Some of this inferior product went to your organization.
为了这个。
And for that...
我必须道歉。
I must apologize.
真诚地。
Sincerely.
什么建筑工程？
What construction project?
我的意思是，你说德国人正在建造一些东西。
I mean, you said the German was building something.
什么？
What?
啊。
Ah.
对我来说，向你展示会更简单。
It would be simpler for me to show you.
当完成时，这将是
When finished, this will be
最先进的排内冷却系统
the most advanced in-line chilling system
在西南部。
in the Southwest.
-冷冻鸡肉？-冷冻机。
- A chicken freezer? - Chiller.
我们的产品从未冷冻过。
Our product is never frozen.
这些是齐格勒的人，按照他的计划工作。
These are Ziegler's men, working from his plans.
就他们而言，
As far as they're concerned,
他们的领袖已经回家了。
their leader has gone home.
没有什么能阻止你分享这一切。
Nothing was keeping you from sharing all this.
很多麻烦都是可以避免的。
A lot of trouble could have been avoided.
是的。
Yes.
有许多误解。
There were any number of misunderstandings.
我的男人不知道谁在跟踪他。
My man didn't know who was following him.
因此，
And as a result,
他竭力掩饰自己的行为。
he went to great lengths to conceal his activities.
你的男人…迈克尔，对吗？
Your man... Michael, is that right?
是的。
Yes.
那不是他，是吗？
That's not him, is it?
是的。
It is.
好吧，如果允许的话，我很乐意跟你打招呼。
Well, I'd love to say hello, if that's permitted.
当然可以。
Well, certainly.
迈克尔。
Michael.
迈克尔，请见我的助手爱德华多。
Michael, please meet my associate Eduardo.
真高兴。
What a pleasure.
我听过很多关于你的事。
I've heard so much about you.
对吗？
That right?
哦，是的。
Oh, yes.
我要回到这个问题上。
I'm gonna get back to it.
谢谢你，迈克尔。
Thank you, Michael.
嗯。
Well...
这解释了一切。
that explains everything.
我很高兴你满意。
I am glad you are satisfied.
听我说。
Listen to me.
再也不会有麻烦了。
There must be no more trouble.
你们两个必须共存。
You two must co-exist.
这是没有商量余地的。
This is non-negotiable.
古斯塔沃，再也不会有秘密了。
Gustavo, there can be no more secrets.
是的。
Yes.
Don Eladio不高兴。
Don Eladio is not happy.
你明白我在说什么吗？
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
我知道。
I do.
然后我们就做完了。
Then we are done.
你知道，它会是一个很好的制冷机。
You know, it's gonna be a very nice chiller.
南墙看起来很漂亮。
The south wall's gonna look beautiful.
或者如果我在找……
♪ Or if I'm looking maybe... ♪
头发拉起
♪ Hair pulled up ♪
让我们放松一下吧
♪ Let's take it easy ♪
男：我们在这里做吧！
MAN: Let's do it right here!
哇，哇。
Whoa. Whoa.
后退。
Back off.
对话继续
[CONVERSATIONS CONTINUE]
有很多手机，很多手机。
There are plenty of phones. Plenty of phones.
对不起，女士们，帮不了你。
Sorry. Can't help you, ladies.
每个人都得等轮到他们。
Everybody got to wait their turn.
给你，伙计。
Here you go, buddy.
-下一个！-李摩根的“侧卷机”
- Next! - [LEE MORGAN'S "THE SIDEWINDER" PLAYS]
欢迎，欢迎，坐下来吧。
Welcome, welcome. Take a load off.
在我们谈论电话之前，让我们谈谈你。
Before we talk phones, let's talk you.
我猜，从我们短暂的相识，
I'm guessing, from our brief acquaintance,
你是一个偶尔的人，
that you're a fellow who occasionally,
不是你自己的错，呃，
through no fault of your own, uh,
发现你自己在一两个地方。
finds yourself in a Donnybrook or two.
是的，一个，嗯，指关节喷粉。
Yeah, a, um, knuckle duster.
一场殴斗。
A fistfight.
我在想你可能是某人
I'm thinking you might be someone
世界上有谁能吃到地球上的草药。
who partakes of the herb of the Earth.
我猜你的女士们都很受小伙子们的欢迎。
I'm guessing that you ladies are popular with the fellas.
这可能会导致误解
And this could lead to a misunderstanding
男孩们穿着蓝色的衣服。
with the boys in blue.
向我的小朋友问好。
Say hello to my little friend.
看这里，用红色圈起来了吗？
See right there, circled in red?
它是预先设定好的，准备好了。
It's preprogrammed, ready to go.
速度表上的数字1直接指向我。
Number 1 on the speed dial goes directly to me.
你按下那个，然后……噗！……我在那里。
You press that, and... poof!... I'm there.
-下一个！-为什么打电话给手机男？
- Next! - Why call the cellphone guy?
因为我不只是一个手机人。
'Cause I'm not just a cellphone guy.
我是为你而战的律师。
I'm the lawyer who's gonna fight for you.
你可能会发现自己被占有了
You might find yourself in possession
几件军事条例中，你知道。
of a few pieces of military ordinance, you know...
RPGs，可能是在树干上的粘土更多的地雷。
RPGs, maybe couple claymore mines in the trunk. [CHUCKLES]
在你意识到之前，
Before you know it,
另一个人在人行道上流血
the other guy is bleeding out on the pavement
而警察却给了你邪恶的眼睛。
and the cops are giving you the evil eye.
只是人们总是
It's just that people are always
互相看对方的肩膀。
looking over each other's shoulder.
你没有伤害任何人。
And you're not hurting anyone.
你知道，谁不想成为……
You know, who doesn't want to be...
外面的大个子？他的名字叫Huell Babineaux。
Big fella outside? His name's Huell Babineaux.
去问问休厄尔关于我的事。
Go ask Huell about me.
他面临三年的困难。
He was facing three years.
他面临6年的困难。
He was facing six years.
在瓜达卢佩的8年。
Eight years down in Guadalupe.
他面临25年的挑战。
He was facing 25 years.
一天都没做。
Didn't do a single day.
这就是为什么他称我为“魔术师”。
That's why he calls me the "magic man".
我叫他不要那样叫我，但他坚持。
I asked him not to call me that, but he insists.
-下一个！
- Next!
速度表上的数字1。这是你的生命线。
Number 1 on the speed dial... that's your lifeline.
警察来接你，他们威胁你，他们看着你。
Cops pick you up. They threaten you. They look at you sideways.
你按下那个按钮，我就在那里。
You press that button, and I'm there.
它不只是。按1。
It's not just... Press number 1.
按1，把你的嘴唇拉紧，按下按钮。
Press number 1. Zip your lip and press the button.
闭上你的嘴，按1。
And keep your mouth shut. Press number 1.
把它收起来，噗！
Keep it charged. Poof!
噗！噗！我在那儿。
Poof! Poof! I'm there.
-在速度表上的数字1。
- At number 1 on the speed dial...
这是你的生命线，是你的应急按钮。
It is your lifeline. It's your panic button.
只要按1，按1在速度刻度盘上。
Just press number 1. Press 1 on the speed dial.
直接问我，问他关于“魔术师”的事。
Goes straight to me. Ask him about the "magic man".
按下这个按钮。快速的正义。
Press the button... Speedy justice.
然后，你的朋友扫罗就在那里。
... and, boom, your friend Saul is there.
我一天24小时，一周7天，一年365天。
I got your back 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days a year.
-按1。
- Press number 1.
为你快速伸张正义。只要按1。
Speedy justice for you. Just press 1.
如果这发生了……这是你的生命线。
If and when that happens... Here's your lifeline.
请按1号，好好利用它。
Press number 1. Use it in good health.
在快速拨号上的第一个。直接向我。
Number 1 on the speed dial... Goes straight to me...
……法律上的麻烦……第一个……
... trouble with the law... Number 1...
问他关于“魔术师”的事，请按1。
Ask him about the "magic man". Press number 1.
还有……噗！……索尔古德曼在那里。
And... poof!... Saul Goodman is there.
各位，各位，女士们，先生们，男孩和女孩们，
Folks, folks, ladies and gents, boys and girls,
由于受欢迎的需求，我很抱歉地说
uh, due to popular demand, I'm very sorry to say
-我们已经把最后的电话给了。-
- we've given out our last phone. -
然而，我仍在这里进行法律咨询……
However, I'm still here for legal consultations...
免费法律咨询。
free legal consultations.
你知道吗？至少拿一张牌。
You know what? At least take a card.
你符合法律，你想要法律来见我。
You meet the law, you want the law to meet me.
哇，哇，哇，哇，你知道吗？
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Whoa, you know what?
既然你们今晚没人打电话，
Uh, since none of you are getting phones tonight,
有折扣吗？
how about a special discount?
嗯，嗯，下一个，嗯，两个星期，
Yeah, um, f-for the next, uh, two weeks,
嗯，非暴力的重罪，50%。
um, non-violent felonies, 50% off.
是的。
Yeah.
好的。
Okay.
是吗？那是给你的。
Yeah? That's for you.
-我要一个。-50%。
- I'll take one. - 50% off.
好的，现在我们有了一些接受者。
Yeah. Alright. Now we got some takers.
给你50%的折扣。
There you are. 50% off.
记住，50%的折扣。
Remember, 50% off.
-好的-真的吗？
- Alright. - For real?
哦，是的，是的。
Oh, yeah, yeah.
-很好。-
- Very good. -
做得好，有魔力的人。
Well-done, magic man.
我们才刚刚开始。
We're just getting started.
如果你要死了，你早就死了。
If you were gonna die, you'd be dead already.
现在从卡车里出来。
Now step out of the truck.
我们有事情要做。
We got things to do.
好了。
Alright.
这份工作可能只完成了一半，但你却得到了全额的报酬。
The job may only be half done, but you're being paid in full.
是否需要说你的合作
Does it need to be said that your cooperation
预计会持续下去吗？
is expected to continue permanently?
不是一个词，不是今天，
Not a word, not today,
不是明天，不是下周，不是永远。
not tomorrow, not next week, not ever.
你让你的结束，将会有后果。
You let your end down, there will be consequences.
大家都明白了吗？
Is that understood by all?
好了。
Alright.
Udo和Renke，你在切罗基人。
Udo and Renke, you're in the Cherokee.
钥匙在里面。
Keys are inside.
你要开车去丹佛。
You're driving to Denver.
飞往苏黎世的航班在午夜起飞。
Flight for Zurich leaves at midnight.
你挂在右边，你会在四英里内到达主要的高速公路。
You hang a right, you'll hit the main highway in four miles.
护照和一些票。
Passport and some tickets.
凯，你独自一人在红色的庞蒂亚克。
Kai, you're traveling solo in the red Pontiac.
你要飞出达拉斯。
You're flying out of Dallas.
这是一个很长的车程。
It is a long drive.
航班9:40起飞，直接飞往柏林。
Flight leaves at 9:40, direct to Berlin.
我什么都不会说。
I will never say anything.
永远。
Ever.
这是必须的。
It had to be done.
他是个好人，但是……
He was a good man, but...
事实上，他是软弱的。
in truth he was soft.
丰田卡普斯。
Casper, Toyota.
你要去凤凰城。
You're headed to Phoenix.
10:15到温哥华，然后是温哥华到布达佩斯。
10:15 to Vancouver and then Vancouver to Budapest.
是吗？
Yeah?
他的价值是你的50倍。
He was worth 50 of you.
塞巴斯蒂安，阿德里安。
Sebastian, Adrian.
公民。
The Civic.
你要开车去埃尔帕索。
You're driving to El Paso.
你在7:25到芝加哥，
You're on the 7:25 to Chicago,
然后是芝加哥到维也纳。
then Chicago to Vienna.
嗯？
Well?
他们中的最后一个在一小时前登上了苏黎世的飞机。
Last of them got on a plane for Zurich an hour ago.
没问题。
No problem.
他们会照别人说的去做吗？
Will do they as they've been told?
你在问我的意见？
You're asking my opinion?
我是。
I am.
他们知道后果。
They know the consequences.
还有洗衣服？
And the laundry?
该网站的入口已被封锁。
Entrances to the site have been sealed.
没有人会在这上面栽跟头。
Nobody's gonna stumble on it.
只要拉罗萨拉曼卡就在边境的这一边，
As long as Lalo Salamanca is on this side of the border,
我们不能再继续下去了。
we cannot continue as we were.
这就是它。
So this is it.
不，不是这样的。
No. This is not it.
一旦萨拉曼卡被处理……
Once Salamanca is dealt with...
他将被处理。
and he will be dealt with...
施工将恢复。
construction will resume.
在那之前，你将继续得到报酬。
Until then, you will continue to be paid.
嗯。
Mm.
所以，你要付钱让我什么都不做。
So, you're gonna pay me to do nothing.
把它叫做固定器。
Call it a retainer.
-即使是在齐格勒之后？-是的。
- Even after Ziegler? - Yes.
法兰克福发生了什么？
What happened in Frankfurt?
律师们花了一整天的时间和他的妻子在一起。
The attorneys spent a full day with his wife.
她接受了所提出的事实。
She accepted the facts as presented.
根据你的建议。一个建筑事故。
As per your suggestion... a construction accident.
葬礼在昨天举行。
The funeral was yesterday.
当然，她也得到了补偿。
And, of course, she has been compensated.
“补偿”。
"Compensated".
我会选择我的下一句话
I would choose my next words
如果我是你的话，我会非常小心的。
very carefully if I were you.
嗯。
Mm.
你保留你那该死的护圈。
You keep your goddamn retainer.
奥克利先生，奥克利先生！
WOMAN: Mr. Oakley! Mr. Oakley!
你想评论一下卡尔格雷特霍斯特案吗？
Would you care to comment on the Carl Gravenhorst case?
-哦，我……我……-你知道的，D.A.的办公室
- Oh, I'm... I... - As you know, the D.A.'s office
被指控有不当行为
has been accused of misconduct
在墓中。
in the Gravenhorst case.
你能对最新的进展发表评论吗？
Would you comment on the latest development?
呃，坟墓是什么？
Uh, the Graven what?
人们说你在起诉一个无辜的人。
People are saying you're prosecuting an innocent man.
地方检察官办公室有什么要隐瞒的吗？
Does the D.A.'s office have something to hide?
-嗯，什么，嗯…-吉米：对不起，打扰一下。
- Well, what, um... - JIMMY: Excuse me. Excuse me.
请让我过去。
Please let me through.
呃，那是我的客户，你说的是。
Uh, that's my client you're talking about.
-你是。-我是索尔古德曼，
- And you are... ? - I'm Saul Goodman,
卡尔。格雷夫霍斯特100%是无辜的。
and Carl Gravenhorst is 100% innocent.
阿尔伯克开的办公室
The Albuquerque D.A.'s office
犯下了令人发指的司法不公。
is perpetrating an outrageous miscarriage of justice.
你是谁？
You're who?
我是索尔古德曼。
I'm Saul Goodman.
我们会反诉你
And we are countersuing you
以及整个阿尔伯克开的办公室
and the entire Albuquerque D.A.'s office
对于恶意迫害，非法拘禁，
for malicious persecution, unlawful detention,
以及滥用过程。
and abuse of process.
-真的吗？-是的。
- Seriously? - Yeah.
我们会一直到最高法院。
We'll take this all the way to the Supreme Court.
等我们结束的时候，
By the time we're through,
卡尔。格雷夫霍斯特的名字将被清除，
Carl Gravenhorst's name will be cleared,
我们会得到一个结算，一个现金结算。
a-and we'll receive a settlement, a cash settlement.
好了，够了，我得上法庭了。
Alright. Enough. I've got to be in court.
你…
You...
如果你一定要去，但要知道。
Go if you must, but know this...
我们会再见面的！
we will meet again!
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
你说你的名字是什么？
What'd you say your name was?
我是索尔古德曼，我把它做成我的生意
I'm Saul Goodman, and I make it my business
为阿尔伯克开的市民辩护
to defend the citizens of Albuquerque
反对任何形式的不公正。
against injustices of every kind.
咯咯笑
[CHUCKLES]
哇，你一定很贵吧。
Wow, you must be really expensive, though.
一点也不。
Not at all.
我相信每个男人，女人和孩子
I believe every man, woman, and child
应该以他们能负担得起的价格迅速获得公正。
deserves speedy justice at a price they can afford.
男：你有名片吗？
MAN: Do you have a card?
-不是为了我，为了一个朋友。-是的。
- Not for me, for a friend. - Yes.
呃，请告诉你的朋友
Uh, and please tell your friend
我没有做出任何判断
that, uh, I make no judgments
我一天24小时都有空。
and I'm available 24 hours a day.
呃，我能买一个吗？
Uh, can I get one of those?
-哦，是的。-
- Oh, yeah. -
那我呢？
What about me?
哦，当然。
Oh, sure.
好的，哇。
Okay. Wow.
是的，呃。
Yeah, uh...
我只是。我只是不知道。
I just... I just don't know.
五个月。
Five months.
过度拥挤，
With overcrowding,
你可能会少于两个。
you'll probably do less than two.
是的，是的。
Yeah. Yeah.
考虑到你的前科，
Considering your priors,
量刑指南会让你看一看
sentencing guidelines would have you looking at
2到4年的监禁。
two to four years in custody.
所以。
So...
五个月真的很好，鲍比。
five months is really good, Bobby.
你担心洛伊斯送货的时候会在那里吗？
Are you worried about being there when Lois delivers?
交付？
Delivers?
哦，对了。
Oh, right.
是的，是的，所以，如果我去试一试，
Yeah, y-yeah, so, um... so, if I go to trial,
你会是我的律师，对吧？
you'll be my lawyer, right?
鲍比，你不想去受审。
Bobby, you do not want to go to trial.
但你会是我的律师。
But you'll be my lawyer.
是的，但是去审判将是一个错误。
Yes, but going to trial would be a mistake.
审判总是不可预测的。
Trials are always unpredictable.
在审讯中，检察官会把一切都扔给我们。
At trial, the D.A. will throw everything at us.
-你只是在掷骰子。-是的，掷骰子，是的。
- You'd just be rolling the dice. - Yeah. Roll the dice. Yeah.
我的意思是，我不是想告诉你你的事，韦克斯勒小姐，
I-I mean, I don't mean to tell you your business, Miss Wexler,
但是你把我放在那里，
but you put me up there,
我给人们大眼睛，
I give the people the big eyes,
他们看到了洛伊斯和那个孩子，
they see Lois here and the kid,
-你知道，他们会相信我的。-我相信你。
- y'know, they gonna believe me. - I'd believe you.
鲍比，有一百万个理由不去审判。
Bobby, there are a million reasons not to go to trial.
但这取决于我，对吧？
But it's up to me, right?
是的，是的，但我建议你不要这样做。
Yes, it is, but I'm advising you not to.
很有可能你会离开更多的时间，
Odds are you would end up going away for more time,
不是更少，我说的是你多年的生活。
not less. And I am talking about years of your life.
但我可能不会，对吧？
But I might not, right?
你不想冒这个险。
You don't want to take that risk.
也许我知道，洛伊斯。
Maybe I do. Lois...
不管鲍比怎么说。
Whatever Bobby says.
失陪一会儿。
Excuse me a moment.
请……
Please...
仔细考虑一下。
think this over carefully.
你们俩。
Both of you.
你准备好吃午饭了吗？
You ready for lunch?
有一个新的三明治自动售货机
There's a new sandwich vending machine
在家庭法庭上。
down by family court.
我听说过好东西。
I've heard good things.
对不起，我被困在这里了。
Sorry, I'm stuck here.
真的吗？怎么了？
Really? What's up?
他没有接受这笔交易。
He's not taking the deal.
-谁？那个家伙？
- Who? That guy? -
他不是那个想卖东西的朋克
Isn't he the punk who tried to sell
一套迷你冰箱给卧底警察的平板？
a flatbed of hot mini-fridges to an undercover cop?
你给他买了什么？
What'd you get him?
-五个月-五个月？
- Five months. - Five months?
有他的前科？！
With his priors?!
好吧，他应该跪下来感谢你。
Well, he should be on his knees thanking you.
我正试着说服他不要去受审。
I'm trying to talk him out of going to trial.
不！真的吗？
No! Seriously?
说真的。
Seriously.
你知道吗？
[SCOFFS] You know what?
不叹息。
[SIGHS] No.
不，我们可以解决这个问题。
No. We can fix this.
我来自D.A.的办公室，好吗？
I'm from the D.A.'s office, okay?
我给你的是什么。
I'm giving you what for.
你给我的是什么。
You're giving me what for.
我们会大声的，我们到那边去。
We'll be loud. We will go over there.
我们会创造一个场景，好吗？
We will make a scene, okay?
呃。
Uh...
新的证据浮出了，
new evidence has come to light,
我正以极端的偏见来处理他的交易。
and I'm pulling his deal with extreme prejudice.
我很生气。
I-I'm pissed.
我想永久地把他关起来。
I wanna put him away permanently.
。三级重罪。
-  ... third-degree felony...
但是你和我打架，我会努力的。
But you fight me, I will push back hard.
我们会让那个朋克跪在他的膝盖上
We'll have that punk on his knees
乞求五个月。
begging for the five months.
-我不这么认为。-是的，来吧，金姆。
- I don't think so. - Yeah, come on, Kim.
我们可以这样做。铅管。
We can do this. Lead-pipe cinch.
他是客户，这是他的决定。
He's the client. It's his decision.
它会有什么好处呢
What good is it gonna do
把那个dweeb放在洛斯兰，对吧？
to put that dweeb away in Los Lunas, huh?
你觉得他现在是个混蛋？
You think he's a jackass now?
等他从那个小丑学院回来。
Wait till he gets back from that clown college.
-吉米，不。-是的，但是他的妻子和孩子呢？
- Jimmy, it... No. - Yeah, but what about his wife and kid?
那是他们，对吧？他们怎么样？
That's them, right? What about them?
如果这不是用我们的力量做善事，我不知道那是什么。
If this isn't using our powers for good, I don't know what is.
-我们不会那样做。-但是，金，我们能做到。
- We're not doing that. - But, Kim, we can do it.
-它会起作用的-我不是在欺骗我的客户。
- It'll work. - I am not scamming my client.
但它对梅萨维德很有效。
But it worked for Mesa Verde...
吉米，退后。
Jimmy, back off.
嗯，y。
Well, y...
好的。
Okay.
嗯…
Um...
是的，我在家里见你。
yeah, I'll see you at home.
那是谁？
So... who was that?
一切都好吗？
Is everything alright?
他来自地区检察官办公室。
He's from the district attorney's office.
他们把交易取消了。
They're taking the deal off the table.
呃，那又怎样？
Uh, so what?
我的意思是，我们不会接受它，所以。
I mean, we weren't gonna take it anyway, so...
韦克斯勒小姐，为什么他们要把它从桌子上拿下来？
Miss Wexler, why are they taking it off the table?
我……不确定。
I... don't know for sure.
有可能他们有新的证据。
It's possible they have new evidence.
就像……喜欢……喜欢什么？
Like... Like... Like... Like what?
就像……像……照相机，……或……或目击者或……
Like... Like... cameras or... or... or witnesses or...
我真的不能说。
I really couldn't say.
我们很快就会知道的。
We'll find out soon enough.
博比，我很抱歉。
Bobby, I'm sorry.
看起来他们想要以你为榜样。
It looks like they want to make an example out of you.
呃。
Uh...
好吧，我们最好去告诉法官
Alright, well, we better go tell the judge
我们要把它带到审判中去。
that we're taking this to trial.
是的，你。你知道吗？
Yeah, yeah, you... you know what?
嗯……你确定我们还不能得到五个月的时间吗？
Um... are you sure we still can't get the five months?
D.A.把它从桌子上拿走了。
The D.A. took that off the table.
你的意思是如果你……即使你问的很好？
You mean if you... even if you asked real nice?
我可以试试。
I could try.
你确定这就是你想要的吗？
Are you sure that's what you want?
是的，是的，我想过，
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I-I thought about it,
就像你说的，还有。
just like you said, and...
我可以做五个月。
I could do the five months.
Wexler小姐。请问？
Miss Wexler... please?
在这里等着。
Wait here.
我不能保证什么，但是……
I can't promise anything, but...
我来查一下。
I'll look into it.
当然，当然，你这样做。
Sure, sure. Y-You do that.
我们会。我们就在这里。
We'll... We'll be right here.